<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Breath Alchemist</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Breath Alchemist</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 16:18:12 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Exercise Snacks: A Science Based Method to Combat the Modern Sedentary Lifestyle</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/exercise-snacks-a-science-based-method/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 16:18:12 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/exercise-snacks-a-science-based-method/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;exercise-snacks&#34;&gt;Exercise Snacks &lt;a href=&#34;#exercise-snacks&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Sitting is the new smoking,&amp;rdquo; or so they say.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s be honest, our bodies weren&amp;rsquo;t made to sit for 8 hours per day in a chair, typing on a keyboard. Sure, modern technology has brought many benefits, but sometimes it&amp;rsquo;s easy to forget what we&amp;rsquo;ve lost in the process.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There isn&amp;rsquo;t a doctor in the world, or any medical institution, that can deny that physical exercise is one of the most potent remedies for longevity, stress reduction, and general well-being. We all know that, but we also know that finding time to work out can be very hard.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Alchemy of Rest: NSDR and Yoga Nidra</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/nsdr-and-yoga-nidra/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 11:42:10 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/nsdr-and-yoga-nidra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi there!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My name is…. well, for now you can call me the breath alchemist and this is the first post of — what I hope — will be a long series where I’ll take you trough my journey of practice and discovery of all the arts, disciplines and tools that helped me with my internal “healing”.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;why-breath-alchemist&#34;&gt;Why Breath Alchemist? &lt;a href=&#34;#why-breath-alchemist&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Breath&lt;/strong&gt; = The main “tool” I have been using to reach my goals. This was my “gateway drug” to this world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>L’Alchimia del Riposo: NSDR e Yoga Nidra</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/nsdr-e-yoga-nidra/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 11:09:07 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/nsdr-e-yoga-nidra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ciao a tutti!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Il mio nome è… beh, per ora potete chiamarmi Breath Alchemist e questo è il primo post di quella che spero sarà una lunga serie in cui vi accompagnerò nel mio percorso di pratica e scoperta di tutte le arti, discipline e strumenti che mi hanno aiutato con la mia “guarigione” interiore.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;perché-breath-alchemist&#34;&gt;Perché Breath Alchemist? &lt;a href=&#34;#perch%c3%a9-breath-alchemist&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Breath&lt;/strong&gt; = Il principale “strumento” che ho utilizzato per raggiungere i miei obiettivi. Questa è stata la mia “gateway drug” a questo mondo.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>La Respirazione Wim Hof: Mito o Realtà?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/metodo-wim-hof/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 17:41:26 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/metodo-wim-hof/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p class=&#34;markdown-image&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://miro.medium.com/v2/resize%3Afit%3A1400/format%3Awebp/1%2A4yKYl8iXhRV2jxlGlkfTHw.png&#34; alt=&#34;alt text&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Salve a tutti!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Oggi tratteremo di uno dei trend che negli ultimi anni hanno scisso il mondo del fitness in due: il metodo del tanto rinomato Wim Hof.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;C’è lo ama e chi lo odia, e noi oggi andremo brevemente a riassumere i concetti principali del metodo per poi soffermarci in maniera più approfondita sull’aspetto della respirazione; la respirazione è il pilastro meno conosciuto del suo metodo, essendo meno “scenico” rispetto alle tanto popolari immersioni nel ghiaccio.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Wim Hof Breathing Method: Myth or Reality?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/wim-hof-method/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 17:41:26 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/wim-hof-method/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p class=&#34;markdown-image&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://miro.medium.com/v2/resize%3Afit%3A1400/format%3Awebp/1%2A4yKYl8iXhRV2jxlGlkfTHw.png&#34; alt=&#34;alt text&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hello everyone!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Today we will discuss one of the trends that in recent years has split the fitness world in two: the method of the much-renowned Wim Hof.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are those who love it and those who hate it, and today we will briefly summarize the main concepts of the method and then focus more deeply on the aspect of breathing; breathing is the least known pillar of his method, being less &amp;ldquo;scenic&amp;rdquo; than the very popular ice baths.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
